SATENDRA KUMAR

Sales, marketing & liaising (Trade & institutional sales specialist)

E-Mail: satendrakumar7777@gmail.com | **Contact No.**: 7903521151 | **Location**: Ranchi | **Nationality**: Indian | **LinkedIn**: https://www.linkdin.com/in/satendra-kumar-05aa0828

SUMMARY

20 years of experience in sales and marketing with critical thinking and problem solving along with intense attitude of contributing to the organizational goals by liaising, Networking and maintaining client relations and to accelerate organizational activities in order to achieve its mission & vision along with success & growth in my carrier.

KEY EXPERTISE

Creativity Sales growth techniques Team handling Public speaking Channel & Institutional sales expert liaising

Problem solving Team work Analysis & strategy development

EDUCATION

Graduation : Economics hons. From Ranchi university In 1993-1996

• Intermediate : Arts from Ranchi university in 1993

• Matriculation: Bihar schooling examination board in 1991

•

CERTIFICATIONS

- · Certificate in Network marketing
- Sports authority of India (National player in Track & field event) 110 meter hurdles

EMPLOYMENT

September 2015 - Till present (Working as an independent sales professional) Eastern region for brands like

- BRITANIA, RECKITT & BENCKISER, ADDIDAS, LEE COOPER, UNITED BUSCUITS, TOP RAMEN, BAGRRYS, CARGIL OIL, FORTUNE, TALWAR HOJEREY, DEVDAESHAN AGARBATTI, NEVIA,
- Liaising with IG,DIG of master canteen para military forces & generating bulk orders
- Ensuring supply & chain management
- Collecting payments
- Sales analysis & strategy development for expansion in wider geographical areas/regions.

August 2009 – July 2015: Associate Appliances LTD Institutional sales manager Eastern region (CPC & CSD)

- Look king after Sales growth for the company in entire eastern region
- Liaising with para military force key contact officials & generate the sales (Bulk orders) & clearing the payments
- Meeting & explaining the product properties and schemes to the target customers
- · Collecting information about competitor's brand sales & developing strategy with senior personnel's of the firm
- Team handling
- Reporting & documentation of all the market & sales related data/documents (primary & secondary sales, target achievement) etc

March 2007- July 2009: Area sales manager JAIN Pharmaceuticals

- Ensuring sales growth by liaising with doctors, chemist & medical practicenors
- Ensuring personnel primary & secondary sales target along with team members
- Appointment of new distributors & C&F agents
- Appointment/ recruitment of medical representatives & their training
- Timely collection of payments
- Analysis & strategic development for sales growth

May 2001 - Jan 2007: Medical representative at Jupiter Pharmaceuticals

- Doctors & chemist visits & product presentation
- Ensuring primary & secondary sales target
- · Daily call analysis

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Organizes Entrepreneur & Leadership development workshops
- Motivational Trainer & speaker

_

Hobbies

Singing, playing guitar, sitting in moonlight, travelling, reading auto biographies, developing new ideas related to any business & social reconstruction